Dr. Vladimir O. Talibov

Neversvägen 43 SE 22479 Lund, Sweden $+460728453329 \\ vladimir.o.talibov@gmail.com \\ http://vtalibov.xyz$

Summary

Protein chemist with an interest in early stage drug discovery. Experienced in biosensors, fragment screening, biophysical techniques and structural methods. Keen to set up new expertises and methodologies that are required for a successful project development.

Skills

<u>Experimental</u>: Biophysical methods (SPR, MST, TSA), protein crystallisation, expression&purification, synchrotron-based MX, enzymology.

<u>Computer:</u> *nix, Python (numerical analysis, data processing), T_EX, crystallographic suites, KNIME.

Languages: English, Russian, Swedish (basic).

Expertise: FBLD, early-stage drug design, biophysical methods, protein chemistry.

Experience

Researcher

2019 - current

MAX IV laboratory, Lund, Sweden

- Beamline development and user support as a beamline scientist.
- Design, maintenance and curation of in-house fragment library; development of operational protocols for MAX IV fragment screening facility.

Laboratory Assistant

2012 - 2014

OOO "Biochip-IMB", Moscow, Russia

- Clinical chemistry: development and benchmarking of protein microarray-based diagnostic assays.
- QC of proteins and reactive small molecules.

Education

PhD in Biochemistry

2014 - 2019

Uppsala University, Uppsala, Sweden

Biophysical methods, protein crystallography.

Thesis: "Interaction kinetic analysis in drug design, enzymology and protein research"

BSc&MSc in Chemistry

2008 - 2013

Moscow State University, Moscow, Russia

Interests

Protein chemistry, methods for FBLD, drug design, protein-ligand interfaces.

Publications

*

References